<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Musical Zodiac</string>

    <!-- Main -->
    <string name="content_description_image_about">image about</string>
    <string name="content_description_image_author">image author</string>
    <string name="content_description_image_interpreter">image interpreter</string>
    <string name="main_makrokosmos">Musical Zodiac</string>
    <string name="main_about">About</string>
    <string name="main_author">George Crumb</string>
    <string name="main_interpreter">Fabio Álvarez</string>
    <string name="contentDescription_expand">expand</string>

    <!-- Song List -->
    <string name="title_songListActivity">Musical Zodiac</string>
    <string name="tab_name_volume_1">Volume one</string>
    <string name="tab_name_volume_2">Volume two</string>
    <string name="content_description_cd_image">CD image</string>
    <!-- Song Detail -->
    <string name="time_format" translatable="false">%d:%02d</string>

    <!-- CD songs -->
    <string name="title_cd_title" translatable="false">Musical Zodiac</string>
    <string name="volumeITitle" translatable="false">Volume one</string>
    <string name="volumeIFirstSongTitle" translatable="false">1.- Primeval Sounds</string>
    <string name="volumeIFirstSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Genesis I</string>
    <string name="volumeISecondSongTitle" translatable="false">2.- Proteus</string>
    <string name="volumeIThirdSongTitle" translatable="false">3.- Pastorale</string>
    <string name="volumeIThirdSongSubTitle" translatable="false">From the Kingdom of Atlantis, ca. 10,000 B.C.</string>
    <string name="volumeIFourthSongTitle" translatable="false">4.- Crucifixus</string>
    <string name="volumeIFourthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">[SYMBOL]</string>

    <string name="volumeIFifthSongTitle" translatable="false">5.- The Phantom Gondolier</string>
    <string name="volumeISixthSongTitle" translatable="false">6.- Night-Spell I</string>
    <string name="volumeISeventhSongTitle" translatable="false">7.- Music of Shadows</string>
    <string name="volumeISeventhSongSubTitle" translatable="false">For Aeolian Harp</string>
    <string name="volumeIEighthSongTitle" translatable="false">8.- The Magic Circle of Infinity</string>
    <string name="volumeIEighthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Moto Perpetuo [SYMBOL]</string>

    <string name="volumeINinthSongTitle" translatable="false">9.- The Abyss of Time</string>
    <string name="volumeITenthSongTitle" translatable="false">10.- Spring-Fire</string>
    <string name="volumeIEleventhSongTitle" translatable="false">11.- Dream Images</string>
    <string name="volumeIEleventhSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Love-Death Music</string>
    <string name="volumeITwelfthSongTitle" translatable="false">12.- Spiral Galaxy</string>
    <string name="volumeITwelfthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">[SYMBOL]</string>

    <string name="volumeIITitle" translatable="false">Volume two</string>
    <string name="volumeIIFirstSongTitle" translatable="false">1.- Morning Music</string>
    <string name="volumeIIFirstSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Genesis II</string>
    <string name="volumeIISecondSongTitle" translatable="false">2.- The Mystic Chord</string>
    <string name="volumeIIThirdSongTitle" translatable="false">3.- Rain-Death Variations</string>
    <string name="volumeIIFourthSongTitle" translatable="false">4.- Twin Suns</string>
    <string name="volumeIIFourthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">DoppelgÑnger aus der Ewigkeit [SYMBOL]</string>

    <string name="volumeIIFifthSongTitle" translatable="false">5.- Ghost-Nocturne: for the Druids of Stonehenge</string>
    <string name="volumeIIFifthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Night-Spell II</string>
    <string name="volumeIISixthSongTitle" translatable="false">6.- Gargoyles</string>
    <string name="volumeIISeventhSongTitle" translatable="false">7.- Tora! Tora! Tora!</string>
    <string name="volumeIISeventhSongSubTitle" translatable="false">Cadenza Apocalittica</string>
    <string name="volumeIIEighthSongTitle" translatable="false">8.- A Prophecy of Nostradamus</string>
    <string name="volumeIIEighthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">[SYMBOL]</string>

    <string name="volumeIINinthSongTitle" translatable="false">9.- Cosmic wind</string>
    <string name="volumeIITenthSongTitle" translatable="false">10.- Voices from "Corona Borealis"</string>
    <string name="volumeIIEleventhSongTitle" translatable="false">11.- Litany of the Galactic Bells</string>
    <string name="volumeIITwelfthSongTitle" translatable="false">12.- Agnus Dei</string>
    <string name="volumeIITwelfthSongSubTitle" translatable="false">[SYMBOL]</string>

    <!-- zodiac signs -->
    <string name="zodiacSign_aries">Aries</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_taurus">Taurus</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_gemini">Gemini</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_cancer">Cancer</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_leo">Leo</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_virgo">Virgo</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_libra">Libra</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_scorpio">Scorpio</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_sagittarius">Sagittarius</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_capricorn">Capricorn</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_aquarius">Aquarius</string>
    <string name="zodiacSign_pisces">Pisces</string>
    <string name="contentDescription_zodiacSign">Zodiac symbol</string>

    <!-- Info -->
    <string name="infoAbout_title">About</string>
    <string name="infoAbout_body">“Music is a system of proportions in the service of a spiritual impulse”\nGeorge Crumb\n\n
        Makrokosmos I &amp; II (1972/73) is one of the most complete and influential cycles of the new technical resources of the piano from the latter twentieth century.\n\n
        The first volume is composed in memory of Béla Bartok (1881 - 1945) and dedicated to the pianist David Burge (1930 - 2013) and the second in memory of Gustav Mahler (1860 - 1911) and dedicated to the pianist Robert Miller (1930) - 1981).\n\n
        Each piece is assigned a zodiac sign reflecting his preoccupation with time and space.\nEach volume is divided into three parts, themselves sectioned into four parts that are to be played without interruption.  Crumb designed the fourth piece of each part in the form of a symbol in relation to the composition. In the first volume: Crucifixus as a cross, The Magic Circle of Infinity as circle and Spiral Galaxy as a spiral (picture on the back cover).\n\n
        Both volumes subtitled: Twelve pieces of fantasy after the zodiac for amplified piano. Twenty-four pieces that constitute a massive and detailed exploration of the sonorous possibilities of the piano, creating a virtuous synthesis between the conventional pianism (keyboard) and the unconventional (inside the piano), including the pianist through whispers, whistles, chants or shouts.\n\n
        Crumb exploits all the pianistic color tones imaginable on the keyboard and inside the piano by traversing the entire pitch range of the instrument, using the three pedals, exploiting an (extraordinarily wide dynamic range through amplification), using the pianist\'s hands to strike, pluck and scrape the strings and through the use of objects: chains, glass tumblers, metal plectrums, metal thimbles, sheets of paper or a wire brush.\n
        Fabio Álvarez\n\n
        George Crumb, Makrokosmos Volume I Notes*:\n
        “The title and format of my Makrokosmos reflect my admiration for two great 20th century composers of piano music – Béla Bartók and Claude Debussy. I was thinking, of course, of Bartók\'s Mikrokosmos and Debussy\'s 24 Preludes. However, these are purely external associations, and I suspect that the “spiritual impulse” of my music is more akin to the darker side of Chopin, and even to the child-like fantasy of Schumann.\n\n
        And then there is always the question of the “larger world” of concepts and ideas which influence the evolution of a composer\'s language. While composing Makrokosmos, I was aware of certain recurrent haunting images. At times quite vivid, at times vague and almost subliminal, these images seemed to coalesce around the following several ideas (given in no logical sequence, since there is none): the “magical properties” of music; the problem of the origin of evil; the “timelessness” if of time; a sense of the profound ironies of life (so beautifully expressed in the music of Mozart and Mahler); the haunting words of Pascal: “Le silence éternel des espaces infinis m\'effraie” (“The eternal silence of infinite space terrifies me”); and these few lines of Rilke: “Und in den Nächten fállt die schwere Erde aus allen Sternen in die Einsamkeit. Wir alle fallen. Und doch ist Einer, welcher dieses Fallen unendlich sanft in seinen Händen halt” (And in the nights the heavy earth is falling from all the stars down into loneliness. We are falling. And yet there is One who holds this falling endlessly gently in his hands”).\n\n
        Each of the twelve “fantasy-pieces” is associated with a different sign of the zodiac and with the initials of a person born under that sign. I had whimsically wanted to pose an “enigma” with these subscript initials; however, my perspicacious friends quickly identified the Aries of Spring-Fire as David Burge, and the Scorpio of The Phantom Gondolier as myself.\n\n
        Makrokosmos, Volume I was premiered at Colorado College (in Colorado Springs) on February 8, 1973.\n
        Makrokosmos, Volume II was premiered by Robert Miller in New York City (Alice Tully Hall) on November 12, 1974.\n\n
        *Excerpted from notes written for the Nonesuch recording of Makrokosmos Volume I (recorded performance by David Burge, Nonesuch H-71293).\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="infoAuthor_title">George Crumb</string>
    <string name="infoAuthor_body">George Crumb (b. 1929) is one of the most frequently performed composers in today\'s musical world. Crumb is the winner of Grammy and Pulitzer Prizes, and continues to compose new scores that enrich the lives of all who come in contact with his profoundly humanistic art. Crumb\'s music often juxtaposes contrasting musical styles, ranging from music of the western art-music tradition, to hymns and folk music, to non-Western musics. Many of Crumb\'s works include programmatic, symbolic, mystical and theatrical elements, which are often reflected in his beautiful and meticulously notated scores.\n\n
        A shy, yet warmly eloquent personality, Crumb retired from his teaching position at the University of Pennsylvania after more than 30 years of service. Honored by numerous institutions with honorary Doctorates, and the recipient of dozens of awards and prizes, Crumb makes his home in Pennsylvania, in the same house where he and his wife of more than 60 years raised their three children. George Crumb\'s music is published by C.F. Peters and an ongoing series of "Complete Crumb" recordings, supervised by the composer, is being issued on Bridge Records.\n\n
        Conversation between\n
        George Crumb, composer\n
        Fabio Álvarez, pianist\n
        December 15th, 2017\n
        Media, Pennsylvania, USA\n\n
        Fabio Álvarez (FA): When did you start composing?\n\n
        George Crumb (GC): I think I was about nine or ten years old. Needless to say, these early efforts were of no consequence whatsoever! My father was a clarinetist, my mother a cellist, and my brother a flutist. So I wrote little pieces for these instruments (with myself at the piano!). My most valuable education from my early years came from my father´s collection of miniature Eulenburg scores (at least 400 in number!). I was able to learn much about notation while reading these when listening to recordings or concerts on the radio. Stravinsky once said that “composing is notation” and I learned a lot about notation by reading scores.\n\n
        FA: Which were your earlier influences?\n\n
        GC: I don´t remember hearing much really contemporary music at a young age. Growing up in West Virginia in the 1930s meant have that even Debussy passed for “contemporary”! Very occasionally one hear radio broadcasts of certain American composers like Copland or barber, and during the war years we got some Shostakovich (like his 5th Symhony).\n\n
        FA: What do you personally consider to be incisive moments in your student career?\n\n
        GC: As a teenager, I got to know Bela Bartók (works like Concerto for Orchestra, the string quartets, Makrokosmos VI. I count Bartók as one of my most important influences as a composer! I also got to know some Hindemith and Alban Berg during those years.\n\n
        FA: How do you see the importance of timbre in contemporary composition?\n\n
        GC: I feel it is hugely important! Bartók´s expansion of timbre in his quartets, the timbral explosion in the percussion area, and of course the use of new piano timbres in Cage and Cowell.\n\n
        FA: Do you feel it is important that audience is able to deduce the processes and ideas behind a work purely on the basis of hearing the music?\n\n
        GC: Hopefully, yes. And if that doesn´t happen, what´s the point, right?\n\n
        FA: How important is it for you to work closely with the artists performing your works?\n\n
        GC: It is very important to know a performer´s style, technical strong points and personality. All of these things could certainly affect one´s approach to actual composition. But after the premiere of a composition written for a certain performer, one hopes that the work will be taken over by other performers.\n\n
        FA: Of course the effect of a piece doesn´t depend merely on the performance of the musicians, but also on the acoustic of the hall it is performed in. Do you fear that some halls are not very appropriate for the performance of some of your music?\n\n
        GC: I feel that my music (and all music, for that matter) works best in halls that are not too dry! But I have found that my preference for the amplified piano can often be useful in correcting a bad acoustic to some extend.\n\n
        FA: Do you feel that contemporary compositions should reach the attention of a wider audience?\n\n
        GC: It´s a great mystery to me why some compositions can capture the ears of an audience while others cannot. Perhaps it has little to do with compositional style or technique but rather lies in something impossible to define. Some musical works excite the imagination by drawing the listener into a new world of sound and ideas. Other works seem empty and pretentious and lacking in originality. Even the greatest composer can sometimes produce music below their normal excellence. Perhaps the simple answer is to say that if the composer is inspired, the listener will also be inspired!\n\n
        FA: Should a composer write for the musicians who will play a piece or write for the audience who will hear it?\n\n
        GC: For both!\n\n
        FA: You composed the first volume of your Makrokosmos in 1972. This work remains the most comprehensive and influential exploration of new technical resources for the piano of our time. Who were your influences?\n\n
        GC: At the time I wrote Makrokomos I had not heard a single note of John Cage or Henry Cowell. And of course my approach to the piano has nothing to do with Cage´s “prepared piano”. But Cowell produced some sounds in direct contact with the strings and I could be described as his direct descendant!\n\n
        FA: Like the Debussy Preludes, each of your Makrokosmos pieces has an evocative title and a sign of the zodiac, with the initials of a person born under that sign. Why did you use the zodiacal symbols?\n\n
        GC: It was simply another device to unify the work. I use many zodiacal signs of favourite composers like Gutav Mahler and Bela Bartók, but also signs of friends and even family!\n\n
        FA: You are a scorpio and I am a scorpio. Is the personality of each sign related to the character of each piece?\n\n
        GC: I read about the zodiac to learn particulars about each sign. That influenced me, but not profoundly.\n\n
        FA: In Makrokosmos II, you use glass tumblers on the strings to produce a haunting effect.\n\n
        GC: I love the mysterious effect of a glissando over the strings of the piano. Audiences can hardly believe that such sounds can be produce on a grand piano.\n\n
        FA: What are your principal compositional challenges?\n\n
        GC: Constructing a piece that you feel has a form that works and which projects exactly what you want to project spiritually (with the least possible number of notes!).\n\n
        FA: As a pianist from Spain, I must ask this question. One of the pieces of Makrokosmos I (Dream Images), is dedicated to the Spanish poet Federico García Lorca. How has Lorca influenced your music?\n\n
        GC: Profoundly! Twelve or so of my vocal works use poems of Lorca. I love the evocative images in his poetry
    </string>

    <string name="infoInterpreter_title">Fabio Álvarez</string>
    <string name="infoInterpreter_body">Spanish pianist Fabio Álvarez combines musicality, great temperament and a talent for communication in his performances. He expresses his passion for music through his concerts with interpretive commentary and his commitment to art\'s social role in his participation in benefit concerts.\n\n
           Sponsored by three foundations (Cum Laude, Gondra Barandiarán and FIDAH) and more than 60 private patrons Mr. Álvarez got his Master\'s student under the tutelage of the renowned concert pianist and pedagoge Phillip Kawin at Manhattan School of Music.\n\n
           Since studying with the French pianist Emmanuel Ferrer-Lalöe in Musikene (Basque Country, Spain) recent solo engagements have taken him to France, Portugal, Spain and the U.S.A performing at various venues as a recitalist and soloist with orchestra including:  Carnegie Hall (New York, USA), Greenfield Hall (New York, USA), Theatre Elysium Camps (Bilbao, Spain), Orfeón Donostiarra (Donostia, Spain) or Le Prieuré du Mesnil Saint Martin (Aquitaine, France).\n\n
           Fabio has specialized in many other fields as contemporary piano with Anthony de Mare and Ricardo Descalzo, vocal accompaniment with Raymond Beegle and Maciej Pikulski, chamber music with Irini Gaitani and Gabriel Loidi and organ with Dr. Katherine Meloan. promoting and premiering pieces for solo piano and chamber music by contemporary composers.\n\n
           He has been selected to participate in several international music festivals such as the 55th International University Seminar "Música en Compostela" (Santiago de Compostela, Spain), entirely dedicated to Spanish Music; the 3rd Vigo Cultural Circle Seminar or the International Piano Festival "Jesús González Alonso".\n\n
           Fabio has participated in many masterclasses with distinguished pianists and pedagoges, including: Ivo Pogorelich, Eldar Nebolsin, Imre Rohman, Julian Martin, Robert McDonald, Josep Colom, Marta Zabaleta, Ricardo Requejo, Jose Ramón Mendez, James Giles, Nino Kereselidze, Gustavo Díaz Jerez, Mariana Gurkova, Jean-Philippe Guillo, Aurélie Forre, María Jesús Crespo, Maria Teresa Perez and Alexander Kandelaki.
    </string>
    <string name="label_play">play</string>
    <string name="label_pause">pause</string>
    <string name="label_next">next</string>
    <string name="label_previous">previous</string>
    <string name="contentDescription_mediaSeekBar">media seek bar</string>
    <string name="contentDescription_play_or_pause">play or pause</string>
    <string name="contentDescription_play_bar_toolbar">play bar toolbar</string>
</resources>
